Truth be told, what was our assignment this time, anyway?
結局　今回の依頼って何だった訳
Ultra good question.
さあ　超疑問です
We were told to come here to stop an arms deal,
武器取引を阻止しろと言われて　来てみれば
but there isn't even a stray cat around here.
取り引きどころか　猫の子一匹いやしない
Instead, one of these toys starts attacking us.
その代わりに　こんな玩具が襲ってくるなんてね
What's the matter, Takitsubo?
どうしました　滝壺
I've got a weird feeling about this.
なんか　変な感じが
Mugino!
麦野
ありがとう
Thanks.
No problemo.
超問題ありません
Jeez, don't scare me like that, all right?
もう　脅かすなっつのう
Thank you, Mugi—
サンキュー　麦…
Adequate results for the field test.
試運転としては　充分な成果だ
We're steadily gathering data for the real thing—
本番へ向けて　着々とデータが揃って
Aritomi.
有富
Man, my stomach hurts...
お腹苦しい
That's the first time I've ever had turtle.
あたし　すっぽんなんて初めて食べたの
The beef Misaka brought was amazing too.
御坂さんのお肉も凄かったですよね
I ate way too much of it.
お陰で　食べ過ぎちゃいました
Maybe you should take something.
お薬飲んでいた方がいいかも
Come to think of it, how did the talk with your teacher go?
そう言えば　どうでした　先生との話
Well, we found the perfect spot.
丁度いいところが見つかったの
Oh, did you?
そうですか
Then it's almost time, huh?
いよいよですね
Yeah.
A blazing hope is blasting through the city
輝く希望が　この街を駆け抜けるから
闪耀光芒的希望 从城市中起跑
It gives me the strength to hold hands with my trusted friends
いつだって　信じあえる仲間と手を繋ぎながら
无论何时 都与信赖的伙伴们握紧双手
and keep looking for a tomorrow that will satisfy us
心のまま　信じる明日を探し続けてる
相信自己 继续追寻着坚信的未来
A Certain Scientific Railgun
立ち尽くす雑踏の中　遠ざかる君を見つめてた
站在繁杂的人群中 找寻身在远方的你的身影
On a crowded street I saw your shape drawing away
Because we understand the love we share now
分かち合うその大切さ　今は分かっているから
分享彼此的珍贵 现在我们已互相了解
smiles light up around me
いくつもの笑顔が　今日も彩って
无数的笑容如今仍明艳动人
and brighten our days
皆を包み込む そんな当たり前を 守りたい
在我身边的那些习以为常 全都想要守护
I want to protect that simple happiness
Once my dreams start coming true, with the sky as my witness,
動き出す夢を　この空に響かせたら
横空出世的梦想 在空中回响
I will begin to have power over my reality
揺ぎ無い力　現実を捉えてゆく
凭借无可撼动的理想 要将现实捕捉
弱さ打ち明ける　そんな強さを持ってたから
拥有能坦诚弱小的强大力量
I had the strength to talk about my fears
I won't forget when it was that I did
いつの日も忘れないよ　この絆だけ抱きしめて
不论何时难以忘怀 拥抱这份羁绊
I will hold dear the bonds that bind us
胸を張って　誇れる未来を撃ち貫いてく
都能充满信心 击穿值得自豪的未来
and blast open a path to a future I can be proud of
Well?
で　誰だったんですか
Who was that?
That nice-looking guy just now.
さっきの爽やかな人
Oh, someone I know.
ただの知り合いよ
There you go again. Ah!
またまた
Is that the guy you made the cookies for?
ひょっとして例のクッキーの
N-No, no.
違う違う
I'm in over my head with how much he's been haunting me lately!
ここんのとこ　付きまとわれて困ってるの
So, just who is the guy you gave the cookies to, anyway?
じゃあ　クッキーを渡したのって結局誰なんです
I'm telling you, it's not—
だから　そんなんじゃ
Milady...
お姉さま
You're late. What've you been doing?
遅いですわよ　一体何を
Let me tell you!
それがですね
Ah! Look, look, the elevator is here!
ほらほら　エレベーター着いたよ
Come on, come on, let's go, guys!
皆行こう行こう
Quickly, quickly, now!
さあ　はやくはやく
What's going on, Misaka?
She's so cute.
どうしたんですか　御坂さん
ホント　可愛いのう
Edasaki Banri
Congratulations, Edasaki!
おめでとう　枝先さん
They told us you're being discharged the day after tomorrow.
あさってなんでね　退院
Oh, thank you.
ありがとう　皆のお陰だよ
The reason I was able to try so hard
夏休み終わるまでに　絶対退院して
and make sure I wore that by the end of vacation
あれ着るんだって
is thanks to all of you.
頑張ることができたから
So everything after you get discharged is taken care of?
で　退院した後のことは決まってるの
Yeah.
Edasaki is going to be living with Haruue.
枝先さんは春上さんと一緒に住むんですよ
Eh?
For real?
そうなの
Yup.
はい
I've been institutionalized for so long, so...
あたし　ずっと施設にいたから
Living all alone would be really hard for her.
いきなり一人暮らしは大変ですもん
That's why I asked my teachers to let Banri and I share a place.
だから先生にお願いしたの
あたしを絆理ちゃんを同じ部屋にって
Really?
そうなんだ
Then you'll be moving again already?
ではまた引越しですわね
Do you need some help?
お手伝いに参りましょうか
It's okay.
大丈夫なの
Uiharu and I already took care of it.
初春さんと一緒にやっちゃったの
You did?
そうなの
Yeah, the movers are coming tomorrow.
ええ　明日には引越し屋さんが来てくれるんです
You don't say.
そうなんだ
You could have asked us, y'know?
水臭いですわね
Haruue told me that she had something else to talk about with Edasaki.
春上さんはもう少し枝先さんと話したいことがあるからって
All right.
そっか
Jeez, Uiharu.
もう　初春ってば
You should have just said something, and we would have helped her move out.
言ってくれたら引越しの手伝いくらいしたのに
It wasn't really that big of a deal.
それが　意外と大したことなかったんですよ
But the whole place is full of boxes at the moment.
お陰で今　部屋の中はダンボールだらけですけど
Come to think of it,
そう言えば
things were pretty crazy when Haruue moved in too, huh?
春上さんが引っ越してきた時も凄かったもんね
And there's even more now than there was then.
あの時よりもっと増えちゃって
Which is odd, since she wasn't even there very long.
短い時間だったのに　不思議ですよね
Oh, yeah!
そうだ
Shirai, it's almost time, isn't it?
白井さん　そろそろ時間じゃないですか
Ah, yeah, you're right.
そうですわね
What, some more Judgment work?
何　また風紀委員の仕事
Yes.
ええ　今回の「学究会」の警備に動員されてまして
We've been asked to do security detail for the upcoming Academic Reach Assembly.
Today we have the preliminary inspection.
今日はその下見なんです
Yeah?
Um...
あの…
Why does a classroom assembly need security?
「学級会」にどうして警備が必要なんですか
Huh?
Oh, it's not that, Saten.
違いますよ　佐天さん
It's not like a classroom assembly,
クラスの「学級会」じゃなくて
but the Academy City Research Forum Assembly,
「学園都市研究発表会」　略して「学究会」です
the "Academic Reach" for short.
The students in Academy City devote themselves daily to studying.
日々勉学に勤しむ学園都市の学生たち
Those with outstanding grades are given a forum for their papers.
その成績優秀者に与えられた研究発表の場
Academy City Research Forum Assembly
Security Advisory
That's what the Academy City Research Forum Assembly is.
それが「学園都市研究発表会」ですわ
Although in this case, grades aren't based on one's ability,
もっとも　この場合　成績というのは能力の優劣ではなく
but on their academic work.
学業のことですけど
So in other words, it's like a Daihasei Festival for nerds?
つもり　頭のいい人たちの大覇星祭みたいな物ですか
Well it's not as exciting as that.
そこまで華やかじゃないけどね
But there are some well-developed presentations and lectures,
けど　思考を凝らした発表とか　講座とか
and all sorts of things.
いろいろあるんですよ
Oh, yeah? I don't know if I get it,
よくわかんないけど
but they're starting some kind of interesting event this year, right?
なんか面白そうなイベントが　今年から始まるんですね
Actually, they have it every year.
あの　毎年やってるんですけど
Really?
ホントに
Do you mean you're gonna help us?
ホントにお手伝いして頂けるんですか
It's a request from a senior member of the club,
部の先輩からの頼まれごとですから
so Kongou, you're not—
何も婚後さんが
What are you on about?
何をおっしゃいますの
If she's a senior to you two,
お二人の先輩ということは　わたくしの先輩も当然
then she's also my senior.
Besides, I haven't been in the area for very long,
それにわたくし　ここに来て日が浅いものですから
so I've never gotten to go to the Academic Reach Assembly.
「学究会」というものを見た事がありませんの
This would be the perfect opportunity to—
丁度いい機会ですから
Kongou! Are you all right?!
婚後さん
大丈夫ですか
R-Ruffian! Would you dare touch me knowing that my name is Kongou Mitsuko...
無礼者
わたくしを婚後光子と知っての…
S-Somebody!
だ…誰か
He stole my purse!
私のカバン
It is at the height of misconduct
白昼堂々　天下の往来で悪事を働くとは不埒千万
that one would do such evil in broad daylight!
And while the sun would allow you to get away with this,
あなたのような悪党は　たとえお天道様が許そうと
I, Kongou Mitsuko, would never allow it!
この婚后光子が許しません
That's our Kongou!
さすがは婚后さん
Wonderful!
鮮やかですわ
Wannai, Awatsuki,
湾内さん　泡浮さん
there's an Antiskill station just over there.
この先に「警備員」の詰所がありますから
Can you call them over for me?
呼んできてくださるかしら
Sure, one second.
ええ　ただいま
Now then...
さてっと
You there, do you have a minute?
君　ちょっといいかな
I saw what you did earlier.
さっきから見ていたんだけど　少しやりすぎじゃないかな
Don't you think you went a bit too far?
Huh?
I don't care if this man is a criminal,
いくら相手が犯罪者だからといって
but my concern is that you use your ability so recklessly.
無闇に能力を使うのは感心しないね
And who do you think—
誰ですの　あなた
There were any number of ways to handle the situation.
事態を収拾する方法なら　他にいくらでもあったはずだ
Like you said, there's an Antiskill station up ahead,
君が言ってたように　この先には「警備員」の詰所があるし
as well as surveillance cameras all over.
監視カメラも設置されている
Just what are you—
一体何を
Let me finish.
さらに言えば
You should recognize how much danger you exposed everyone here to.
君はここにいる人々を危険に晒した事を認識すべきだ
Huh?
Did you not notice?
気がついていないのかい
It was fortunate that you incapacitated him with one shot this time,
今回は幸運にも一撃で無力化できたが
but what if you had failed?
もし失敗していたらどうなっていたか
He would have been enraged,
逆上した彼が　女性や子供を人質にとったかもしれない
and could have taken a woman or a child hostage.
He's right.
それはそうだな　確かに
How scary.
Indeed.
Those abilities aren't foolproof.
怖い
You seem to be quite confident in your ability,
君は自分の能力に自信があるようだが
but abilities don't fix everything.
能力は万能ではない
W-Well...
それは
Just a moment, please!
お待ちください
I don't know who you are...
どこのどなたか存じませんが
But you shouldn't be so hard on her.
何もそこまでおっしゃらなくても
The fact remains that Kongou actually secured the criminal.
婚後さんが犯人を確保したのは事実ですし
You guys...
あなたたち
I'm sorry we took so long.
遅くなって申し訳ありません
The Antiskill officers are on their way now.
今　「警備員」の方はいらっしゃいますわ
Th-Thank you.
ありがとう
Huh?
あら どちらに行かれたのでしょう さっきの方
Where could that guy have taken off to?
I have returned.
ただいまですの
Oh, welcome back, Kuroko.
おかえり　黒子
Why are you so exhausted?
どうしたの　へたちゃって
The preliminary inspection.
「学究会」の下見
I was aware that it was being held across several universities, but still...
会場が複数の大学に分散しているのは承知していましたが
Who knew I'd have to walk around so much?
まさかあんなに歩かされるとは
I walked my damn feet off.
お陰で足が棒ですわ
It's tough being in Judgment.
風紀委員も大変だ
By the way, how is Uiharu doing?
ところで　初春さん　どうだった
Same as always.
いつも通りでしたわ　ちゃんと仕事をこなしてましたの
She carried out her duties admirably.
I see.
そっか
Moving, huh?
引越しか　色々あるよね
There sure is a whole lot to it, y'know?
It was quite a mess when you first moved into this room, huh?
あんたがこの部屋に来た時も　一悶着あったもんね
Are you really bringing that up again?
またそんな昔な話を
It's kind of past the time...
あれはもう時効…
Milady?
お姉さま
Anything can happen. This is Academy City, after all.
いろいろあるよ　学園都市だもん
Yeah.
Oh, I know!
そうだ　疲れてるんなら　マッサージでもしてあげようか
If you're tired, how about I give you a massage?
How about I give you a massage?
マッサージでもしてあげようか
マッサージしてあげようか…してあげようか…してあげようか…
Kuroko?
黒子
Eh?! What?
なに
I'm just going to take a shower first.
先にシャワーを浴びてきますの
Hey...
おい
Uiharu!
初春
Oh c'mon Saten, you always, always do that!
もう　佐天さんってばいつも　いつも
Sorry, sorry.
ごめんごめん
Were you waiting for me?
待っててくれたんですか
Hmm? Oh, uh, I wouldn't say that, no.
いや　別にそういう訳でも
I'm okay, really.
私は大丈夫ですよ
Haruue and I had been discussing this for a long time, now...
春上さんとは随分前から話してたんです
About how when Edasaki got out of the hospital,
枝先さんが退院したら　春上さんと一緒に住むのが一番だって
it would be best if they lived together.
Oh, you did?
そうなんだ
Well, I'd be lying if I said I wouldn't miss her at all.
そりゃ　全然寂しくないって言ったら嘘になりますけど
But still, I was thinking,
でも 私思うんです
Clothes
the best thing is for the two of them to be together.
やっぱり　二人は一緒にいた方がいいって
Besides, it's not like she's moving far away.
それに　別に遠くに行っちゃう訳じゃありませんし
Once the term starts, we'll be seeing each other at school every day.
新学期になれば　毎日学校で会いますから
Yeah, that's true.
そっか　そうだね
Good, good. That's a load off my mind.
よしよし　お姉さんは安心したぞ
Oh, c'mon, Saten!
もう　佐天さんってば
Yeah.
You're all right, then?
大丈夫だね
#18 "Moving"
A Certain
Scientific Railgun
S
Yes.
はい
I'm sorry to keep you all waiting.
皆　お待たせ
What do you think?
どう…かな
Great! Absolutely great!
いい　すごくいい
It looks good on you!
とても似合ってます
Thank goodness!
よかった
Oh yeah, when you were talking together before,
この前二人が病院に残って話したのは　この事だったんですね
was it about this?
Yeah!
I couldn't wait for everyone to see me wearing it.
みんなに早く見てもらえたかったから
Go on, Milady.
ほら　お姉さま
Oh, right.
そうだった
Edasaki, congratulations on getting released.
枝先さん　退院おめでとう
Congratulations!
おめでとうですの
Thank you!
ありがとう
Well, should we get going, then?
じゃあ　早速行きますか
Huh? Where to?
どこに
A little bit of a celebration!
退院のお祝いなの
We have a reservation at a restaurant with delicious cakes!
ケーキの美味しいお店を予約してあるんですよ
Huh? Cakes?
ケーキ　ありがとう
Thank you!
This is Shirai.
はい　白井ですの
Konori?
固法先輩
Huh? Traffic signal trouble?
信号トラブル
Huh?! It wasn't me!
あたしは何もやってないわよ
All the signals are down in this area.
このあたりの信号が軒並みダウンしてるの
I'm sorry to ask this, but can you get over here?
悪いけど　すぐ来てもらえない
Yes, yes.
As you wish.
了解しましたの
Huh? You're going too, Uiharu?
初春さんも行っちゃうの
Well, I...
それは
Oh, you couldn't.
そんな
Edasaki is just getting out of the hospital.
せっかくの枝先さんの退院ですし
I can cover this by myself—
ここはわたくしだけでも
What are you talking about?
何言ってるんですか
I'm a member of Judgment!
私だって風紀委員です
Please, start without us.
先に始めててください
We'll be there as soon as this is taken care of.
終わったらすぐに駆けつけます
Then we'll see you later.
いってらしゃいなの
Good luck with work!
お仕事頑張って
Right.
はい
Okay, Shirai.
それじゃあ　白井さん
Huh? Oh, yeah.
Well, then.
では
They disappeared!
消えた
Well, we should get going then.
じゃあ　とりあえずいっこか
Not exactly as we planned it, but yet again—
ちょっと予定が狂っちゃったけど
Congratu
lations
Edasaki
Congratu
lations
Edasaki
まあ　改めて
Congratulations!
退院おめでとう
Thank you!
ありがとう
Delicious!
美味しい
Isn't it?
でしょう
Uiharu said that if we were going to celebrate, it had to be here,
初春がお祝いやるなら　絶対ここだって
and she took care of the reservations and the cake.
予約からケーキの手配まで　全部やっちゃったんだよ
Uiharu is really something else, isn't she?
ホントに初春さんってすごいですよね
Before getting released,
退院前もね　引越しの手配や編入の手続きを手伝ってくれたり
she came to help me get moved and took care of the admission.
Right?
Yeah.
Oh, yeah? Really?
そうだったんだ
It's true. The people who join Judgment are amazing.
やっぱり風紀委員になる人って　凄いんだね
Knowing how thrilled you are,
そんなに喜んでもらえたら　初春さんも選んだ甲斐があったわね
I guess it was worth letting her choose, huh?
Yeah, for sure!
ホントホント
I mean, this is really delicious!
だってホントに美味しいし
Is that the key to your new place?
新しい部屋の鍵
Oh, yeah.
Uiharu has been pretty enthusiastic, huh?
随分張り切ってたんだね　初春
She was when it was my turn, too.
あたしの時もそうだったの
You mean, when you moved in?
春上さんが引っ越してきたとき
Oh, yeah. Yeah.
そうそう　あの時も凄い張り切ってたっけ
She was really eager back then, too, huh?
I'd have been anxious if I was alone,
一人で不安だったけど
but Uiharu was there for me.
初春さんがいてくれて
So now it's my turn to make an effort.
だから　今度はあたしが頑張る番なの
Just like what Uiharu did for me,
初春さんがしてくれたみたいに あたしが絆理ちゃんにしてあげるの
I'll do what I can for Banri.
Yeah.
そっか
I hope Uiharu gets here soon.
初春　早く来ないかな
I'm sure she's giving it her all, even now.
きっと　今も一生懸命お仕事してるの
Wearing an ugly helmet,
似合わないヘルメット被って
and directing traffic or something, huh?
交通整理とかやってるのかね
She could ease up at a time like this though.
こんな時くらい　手を抜けばいいのに
Not being able to is really what makes her Uiharu.
それができないのは初春さんなの
That's true.
だね
Maybe I should join Judgment too.
あたしも風紀委員になろうかな
Huh? When did you decide that?
どうしたの　急に
Well, if I did, I could be like Uiharu maybe.
そうしたら　初春さんみたいになれるかなって
I don't think Uiharu has been so nice to you just because she's in Judgment, Edasaki.
初春さんは風紀委員だから
枝先さんに優しくしてた訳じゃないと思うよ
Then why?
じゃあ　なんで
Because she's your friend, right?
友達だから でしょう
Oh, yeah.
そっか
Ah, getting released, huh?
でも退院か
Oh, nothing. Someone else I know is also in the hospital.
いやね　あたしの知り合いも入院してて
I was just wondering, when they get out,
あいつらも退院したら こうして一緒にご飯とか食べられるのかなって
if we could eat together just like this.
Oh, no! Don't worry about it!
いや　気にしないで　そんな大した事じゃないんだから
It's not a big deal! Really!
ホントに
I hope they get released soon too, then.
その人も　早く退院出来るといいね
Yeah, thanks.
ありがとう
Good job today.
お疲れ様
Sorry to call you like that out of the blue.
悪かったわね　急に呼び出しちゃって
I have to say though, signal trouble, of all things...
それにしても　信号トラブルだなんて
There was apparently some irregularity in the electrical system.
なんか　電気系統の異常だったみたい
It's really unusual for something like that to happen here.
珍しいですわね
この町でそんな事が起きるなんて
Shirai!
白井さん
Oh, right.
そうでしたの
Well, we'll be—
では　わたくしたちは
Jeez, what's with you?!
なんですの　もう
There's somewhere I need to be!
私　行きたい所があるんです
Yes, I know. So let's—
分かってますわ　ですから
No, not there! There's a place I need you to take us first!
違うんです
その前に　寄ってもらえたい所があるんです
What should we do? Should we call them?
どうしよう　電話してみる
Yeah, maybe.
そうですね
Okay, yeah, let's try calling them.
いいや　電話しちゃいましょう
Sorry to keep you wai—
お待たせしま…しました
Waiting.
Yes.
ですの
Oh, you finally made it!
やっと来た
Jeez, Uiharu, you're late!
もう初春遅いぞ
Edasaki said she was stopping by the hospital and already left, y'know!
枝先さん病院寄るからって先に帰ちゃったじゃない
Huh? She did?!
そうなんですか
I-I'm sorry!
す…すいません
That's all right.
大丈夫なの
Banri said that the cake was delicious.
ケーキ美味しかったって　絆理ちゃん
Um, here.
あの　これ 枝先さんと食べてください
Please eat these with Edasaki.
Taiyaki?
鯛焼き
Listen, Uiharu, we've been eating cake while you've been gone.
あのさ　初春　あたしたち　今までケーキ食べてたんだけど
W-Well, I know that, but...
そ…それはそうですけど
Having taiyaki after cake is a little...
ケーキの後に鯛焼きとか
No, y'see, I...
いえ　ですからそれは
There, I told you so.
だから言いましたのに
Now, now, it's the little things that go a long way—
まあまあ　気は心っていうか
No, y'see—
だから
It's the same taiyaki as before.
あの時の鯛焼きなの
It's the same kind you bought for me
これ　あたしが凄く不安だったとき 初春さんが買ってきてくれたの
when I was so nervous about moving in.
They taste so good...
とても美味しいの
Huh? H-Hold on, Haruue!
ちょっと　春上さん
I'm so hopeless! I wasn't going to cry today, either!
ダメなの　今日は泣かないつもりだったのに
Um...
あの
I'm
あたし　頑張るから
going to do my best.
Just like you did, Uiharu.
初春さんみたいに　絆理ちゃんのために頑張るから
I'm going to do my best for Banri.
It's all right. Knowing you, Haruue,
大丈夫ですよ　春上さんなら　きっと大丈夫です
I'm sure it'll be all right.
Uiharu...
初春さん
春上さん　そんな　大袈裟ですよ
Haruue... Y'know... It's not such a big deal...
My, my, such children...
まあまあ　お子様ですこと
What can you do?
しょうがないな
It's not hurting anyone.
いいじゃない
I...
私…春上さんの力になれたでしょうか
wonder if I was of any help to Haruue.
What're you saying?
何言ってんの　なれたに決まってんじゃん
Wasn't it obvious that you were?
Ow!
痛…
And not just Haruue, either.
春上さんだけじゃないよ
You helped out Edasaki too, Uiharu.
初春さんは　枝先さんの力にもなれたと思う
Misaka...
御坂さん
Yes, and Milady...
そう　そしてお姉さまは　黒子の力に
You're of help to me—
Well, let's head home then.
さあ　帰ろう帰ろう
Oh right, there's a shortcut up ahead.
そうだ　この先に近道あるんですよ
Hey, are you sure this is the right way?
ちょっと　ホントにこっちでいいの
It's okay. Once we cut through here,
大丈夫　ここを抜けたらあっという間に大通りですよ
we'll be on the main road in no time.
Y'know, I'm surprised you know these things.
でも　ホントよく知ってるわね
Milady? Is something the matter?
お姉さま　どうかなさいまして
Is that...
あれって
Is that a girl?
あれは
女の子
Huh?
Wow, she's cute!
可愛い
Wait, this isn't the time!
それどころじゃありませんの
Ah, hold up, Kuroko!
ちょっと　黒子
She's opening her eyes!
目を覚ましましたよ
Good morning.
おはようございます
Why were you sleeping in a place like this?
どうしてこんな所で寝てたんですか
What's your name?
お名前はなんって言うんですか
Uh, okay. How old are you?
あの　じゃあおいくつですか
Tell me, where do you live? What school do you go to?
ねえ　お家はどこ　学校は
Do you know your teacher's name?
担任の名前とかわかる
This isn't working, is it?
困りましたわね
Maybe she doesn't speak Japanese.
日本語通じないのかな
Oh, no, that's not it, that's not it.
もう　違う違う
When you talk to a little girl,
小さな子と話をする時は　こうしてちゃんと目線を合わせなきゃ
you have to come down to their eye level, like this.
Oh, that looks like some good candy.
美味しそうな飴だね
My name is Ruiko, okay?
私はね　涙子っていうの
What's yours? Can you tell me your name?
あなたは
お名前　言えるかな
Febri.
フェブリ
Febri, is it? Okay, Febri,
フェブリちゃんか じゃあ　フェブリちゃん
anything goes, so tell us whatever you know, okay?
なんでもいいから　知ってることを教えてくれないかな
Misaka Mikoto.
御坂美琴
Huh?
A Certain
Scientific Railgun S
S
Huh?
I walked through our town,
君を知ったこの街は　私には広すぎて
你所熟悉的这个小镇 对我来说有些宽广
but it was too big for me
I tried to hide my discomfort,
焦り不安ごまかして　強がり背伸びした
慌忙来掩盖自己内心的不安 逞强着故作平静
made myself a little taller and pretended to be strong
I got an answer that puzzled me,
見つからない答えに　心は浮かんだまま
对于无法找寻的回答 心中对此怀抱幻想
and everything became complicated
息つぐ暇もなく　時は流れる
在我屏住呼吸的一瞬 时光匆匆流逝
and everything became complicated
My daily life has given me trouble,
繰り返す日常に　苦しくなったなら
对于日复一日的生活 感到痛苦的时候
but I'll take a deep breath
深呼吸一つして　ほら
就深呼一口气 看吧
Above that hill
虹さす　丘の上　目指していこう
向着山丘上那一道彩虹 朝着那里奋斗
I see a rainbow
Let's go find it
I will make sure I will never forget this day
忘れない　今日も刻んでいく
将难以忘怀的今天铭记在心
I'm so happy
出会えたことに　ありがとう
为相遇而心存感谢
I could meet you
It will always be special
きっと　大事だね
一定是很重要的
It will always be special
Let's be proud and walk forward
前を向いて　歩きだそう
向着前方 迈步前进
Our happiness will be our link to tomorrow
明日につなげる笑え合えたね　ありがとう
用彼此的微笑串联明天 心存感谢
When you share
喜びも　悲しみも 分かち合って
不论喜乐哀愁 都要彼此分享
When you share
your happiness and your pain,
さあ　重ねてゆこう
来 一起前进吧
it's twice the fun and half the pain
In this experiment,
今回の実験で　第四位のレベル5に対しても計算通りのデータを得る事ができた
we were able to obtain the data we predicted
for the fourth-ranked Level 5, as well.
We did also have some unanticipated circumstances occur on site,
現場では不測の事態も発生したようだが
but those should be solved shortly.
そちらも程なく解決するだろう
Everything is ready.
準備は整った
Now is the time for us to show our power to this town of esper supremacists.
今こそ僕らの力を　能力至上主義のこの町に見せつける時だ
Those in favor of moving the project to the next phase,
計画を次の段階に進めることに賛成の者は 挙手
raise your hands.
Next Episode
Preview
What's the story with this Febri girl?
何　このフェブリって子
#19 "Academic Reach Assembly"
Why does she know my name?
なんであたしの名前を知ってるの
Could she be lost?
迷子でしょうか
What do we do?
どうしましょう
We'll decide at the Reach Assembly.
「学究会」で決めますの
The Reach Assembly?
「学究会」